hey guys Pastor Ivor Myers here and in
today's video we're going to be taking a
look at yet another mathematical
challenge this time for Christians and
this mathematical challenge is going to
reveal a very
popular
false teaching within Christianity
itself so stay tuned for this math
challenge
thank you
[Music]
all right guys we're going to go ahead
and Jump Right In we're going to begin
our mathematical problem in the book of
Matthew chapter one
in Matthew chapter 1 we have the
genealogy of Christ and within that
genealogy we're going to focus in on the
number of generations from Abraham to
Jesus so Matthew chapter 1 and verse 17
tells us that from Abraham
to David there were 14 Generations from
David to Babylon the Babylonian
captivity there were 14 generations and
then from the Babylonian captivity to
Jesus 14 Generations so 14 plus 14 plus
14 equals 42 Generations all right
please write this down 42 Generations
now
from Abraham to Jesus
there is an estimated time period of 2
000 years this is just generally
speaking
so if we were to take those 2 000 years
and divide those 2 000 years by 42
Generations in other words this is the
time span between Abraham and Jesus it's
2 000 years but it's also 42 Generations
if we were to take 2 000 and divided by
42 Generations we will come to 47 years
in each generation right so 47 times or
47 years times 42 Generations will give
you about 2 000 years okay so that's
simple math now
we want to focus in on a on that first
set of 14 because we're going to be
looking at something God did in the
first set of 14 in other words the the
for the 14 Generations from Abraham to
David
there was a man by the name of Moses who
comes somewhere in the middle uh or
towards the beginning of those 14
Generations so 400 years after Abraham
Moses comes on the scene and you'll
remember that God speaks the Ten
Commandments
from Mount Sinai
during the lifetime of Moses notice with
me Exodus chapter 20 verse 1.
regarding the Ten Commandments the Bible
says and God spake all these words
saying and then we go on to read The Ten
Commandments now I want you to notice
that I have the Strong's Concordance
Hebrew uh um number right after the word
words
and the Hebrew word for this is the word
dabar
and what it means is simply word so God
spoke these words the bar
and then it goes on to list the Ten
Commandments The Ten Commandments are
actually known as the ten words the ten
da bars
so so
keep this in mind because this is going
to be crucial to our mathematical
equation
our mathematical problem
so you'll see this same word the bar
used to refer to the Ten Commandments
again in Deuteronomy chapter 5 verse 22.
these words the bar the Lord speak unto
all your assembly in the mount out of
the midst of the fire out of the cloud
and out of the thick Darkness with a
great voice and he added no more and he
wrote them in two tables of stone and
delivered them unto me we see it again
in Deuteronomy chapter 4 verse 13. and
he declared unto you his Covenant which
he commanded you to perform even Ten
Commandments and now
the word the bar is translated as
Commandments
and he wrote them on two tables of stone
so these ten the bars are the Ten
Commandments now let's take a look at
Psalm chapter 105 and verse 8 because
this is going to be the basis of our
mathematical problem
the Bible says
he hath remembered his Covenant forever
so just think about the verse we just
read he has remembered his Covenant
forever the word
and then guess what the Hebrew is it's
the bar
so we can know that he's referring back
to the Ten Commandments
the word which he commanded uh which he
commanded to a thousand Generations
now how many generations did he command
this word to
to a thousand Generations please keep
this in mind
can we know for sure that this
word to a thousand Generations is
talking about the Ten Commandments well
let's go back to Deuteronomy 7 verse 9.
the Bible says here not know therefore
that the Lord thy God he is God the
faithful God which keepeth Covenant and
mercy with them that love him and keep
his Commandments to what a thousand
Generations ah okay well we know that
Deuteronomy 7 verse 9 is definitely
talking about the Ten Commandments and
guess what is referred to again a
thousand Generations but just to make
sure let's go to one more verse now
we're going to go right to the Ten
Commandments itself and right in the
middle of the Ten Commandments Exodus
chapter 20 verse 6 the Bible says
sowing Mercy unto thousands of them that
love me and keep my Commandments so just
connecting these three verses we can
know with certainty that this is what
God commanded for how long everyone a
thousand Generations a thousand
Generations so what is the problem what
is this mathematical problem that
reveals a very popular error that is
taught amongst
Christians today
well here's the error
if you take
a thousand Generations
and then subtract 42 Generations from
that you're left with
958 Generations
why is this a problem
most Christians today teach
that after 42 Generations now we're
going to go less than that because
remember Moses comes several Generations
after Abraham so let's say somewhere
between 36 and 37 38 Generations okay
maybe even 34 Generations
what most Christians say today
is that 34 Generations 35 36 Generations
after the Commandments were spoken at
Mount Sinai those Commandments now no
longer stand they're done away with the
problem is if we just take 42
Generations just as a just to round It
Off from Abraham to Jesus the problem is
that if you take a thousand Generations
which God said this is how long my
Commandments are going to last
the Christian World by and large has
said no those Commandments are now done
away with when Christ came Christ did
away with the word of God
let that sink in for a moment Christ did
so after 42 Generations we no longer
need to keep the words the ten words
that God spoke out of his own mouth we
don't know we no longer need to keep
those the problem is that that
contradicts the mathematical number
given to us in scripture which is a
thousand Generations
if you take
958 Generations that would be what's
left over what Christians have just cut
off cut off that 915 Generations we
don't need it anymore all 42 Generations
it's done
God said a thousand Generations so we
take 42 away from a thousand you have
958 Generations unaccounted for you have
958 Generations that Christians have
just turned a blind eye to
if you take 958 Generations now remember
a generation
would be 47 years roughly you want to go
40 that's fine you want to go 35 that's
fine let's just take this number 47 for
the sake of our equation
47 times
958 Generations would be 45
000 26 years
it's as if God was saying
till Heaven and Earth pass
it's as if God were saying my
Commandments should be kept
for ever
and in fact let me go back this is
exactly what Psalm 105 verse 8 says let
me just come back let me go back let me
go back Psalm 105 verse 8 he has
remembered his Covenant
for ever
the word dabar which he commanded to a
thousand Generations
000 now is the world going to be around
for 45 000 years after the death of
Christ it's been around for 2 000 years
is it going to be around for for an
additional 43
000 years we don't know but if it were
if it were
this Tech
is telling us
as long as the Earth stands my
Commandments
stand
so now we got a mathematical problem
because most Christians say 42 but the
word of God says a thousand
now
we're going to go to the New Testament
and I'm going to show you something just
to help you see the nature of this
mathematical problem this mathematical
bombshell
that reveals this error
that the law of God the Ten Commandments
the tender bars spoken with God's own
mouth
is no longer relevant
in Hebrews chapter 12 verse 19
. that's the New Testament the Bible
says
and the sounds of a trumpet so it's
speaking about the events that occurred
when God spoke The Ten Commandments it's
just recapping and here's what it says
and the sound of a trumpet and the voice
of the words now the Greek word here for
words is Rima
I need you to keep this in mind which
voice they that heard entreated that the
word and now the Greek word for this
word is logos
should not be spoken to them anymore so
Paul in in recapping what happened back
at Sinai he's equating the debar Old
Testament with the Rhema and the logos
in the New Testament they're wanting the
same thing he's using these words
interchangeably to refer back to the
dabar I just want to focus on this word
Reema for a second because in Matthew
chapter 4 verse 4 the Bible says but he
answered and said it is written man
shall not live by bread alone but by
every word every Rima that proceedeth
out of the mouth of God now let me ask
you a question would this verse include
the tender bars that proceeded out of
the mouth of God at Mount Sinai
one of the only times God spoke to a
that God spoke to this world as a whole
that God spoke to a mass of people
yes God has spoken through prophets
individually but God comes down to this
planet and opens his mouth to speak and
the event is is chronicled in the book
of Exodus is chronicled in Hebrews as
such a major event and the words used
Rima logos in the Old Testament dabar
when Jesus says man shall live by every
word that proceedeth out of the mouth of
God don't you think it would be like the
devil would say yeah but not those words
don't you think it would be like the
devil to take the only time that words
proceeded out of the mouth of God to
humanity
a mass of people and say yeah
you don't need to keep those words
see there's this argument afloat that in
the New Testament you know uh the the
the New Testament doesn't really talk
about the Commandments we don't find the
word Commandments in the Hebrew or in
the Greek but if you go back to the Old
Testament and look at the word use it is
the word davar which is in the New
Testament logos and Rima
and now there's a huge problem because
John 8 verse 47 Jesus said this he that
is of God heareth God's words
Rima
the same word that is used to describe
the dabar in the Old Testament the ten
da bars the word of God and now notice
what he says you therefore hear them not
because you are not of God
we got a mathematical problem on our
hands because the moment we cut off that
thousand generations and say yet 958
Generations don't need to hear the word
of God there is a problem Jesus says you
hear these words not because you are not
of God
that's the problem
that is a huge problem notice with me
James chapter 1 verse 21 wherefore James
says lay apart all filthiness and
superfluity of naughtiness and received
with meekness the engrafted word which
is able to save your soul and again the
Greek word for this word is logos
now I got a question for you what could
he possibly be referring to as the
engrafted word which is able to save
your souls let's go back to the Book of
Exodus 32 and verse 15 to find out what
this engrafted word is
in verse 15 the Bible says and Moses
turned and went down from the mount and
the two tables of the testimony were in
his hand
the tables were written on both their
sides on the one side and on the other
they were written the tables were the
work of God and the writing was the
writing of God Graven upon the tables of
stone
do you see this
the the engraven were the engrafted word
that is able to save our souls is the
same word commanded to a thousand
Generations
can we prove this absolutely Psalm 119
verse 7 the law of the Lord is perfect
is perfect
converting the soul the testimony of the
Lord is sure making wise and simple so
remember what James said let's read it
again wherefore lay apart all filthiness
of
superfluity of naughtiness and receive
with meekness the engrafted word which
is able to save your souls that
engrafted word is the same word Graven
upon the tables and it's the same word
that's Psalm 119 7 says is perfect the
law of the Lord is perfect converting
the Soul Saving the soul
let's follow this through y'all
because second Corinthians 3 and verse 3
carries this thought to its complete and
logical conclusion which is this for as
much as you are manifestly declared to
be the Epistle of Christ ministered by
us not written not with ink but with the
spirit of the Living God not in tables
of stone in other words the tender bars
are no longer to be written on tables of
stone but in the fleshy tables of the
heart listen
what change at the end of the 42
Generations is not the dabar but the
material upon which the tender bars are
written
that's what's changed it's no longer
supposed to just be on Stone we're no
longer supposed to be looking to the
stone it's supposed to be written in our
hearts this is why God said that the the
bar the tender Bars were to last for a
thousand Generations meaning
for ever but Christians have come along
who are teaching this popular teaching
that the tenderbars no longer matter
they were done away with at the end of
42 Generations which we know is a
mathematical lie
God
told us a thousand Generations
and we Now understand that what changed
at the end of the 42 Generations is
simply the material
let's keep moving I need y'all to catch
us I need you to see this because
Hebrews chapter 10 verse 1 tells us this
for the law having a shadow of good
things to come and not with the very
image of the things can never with those
sacrifices which they offered year by
year continually make the comments
they're unto perfect listen to me you
guys
this is not rocket science this is not
difficult mathematics this is very
simple The Ten Commandments contain the
no sacrifices
sacrifices were contained in the law of
Moses the sacrificial law the laws of
offerings and those laws could not make
anything perfect those laws in and of
themselves were not perfect but the law
of the Lord Psalm 19 we just read it is
perfect converting the soul
this law
the law which had which which uh
described sacrifices and offerings that
is the law that was done away with at
the end of the 42 Generations are you
understanding are you following
this is simple mathematics that is what
was done away with but the tender bars
are transferred in the old Covenant from
the tables of stone to in the New
Covenant the tables of the heart it's
still the same 10 de bars now I need you
to follow this
because we're talking about the
significance of the spoken word of God
the word of God do you realize that
there are only two times in all of human
history that the word of God interacted
with the world on a large scale
here are the two verses Psalm 105 verse
8. he has remembered his Covenant
forever the word the bar which he
commanded to a thousand Generations
where was that at Mount Sinai where is
the other place that the word had a
major interaction with the world Psalm
33 verse 6 by the word dabar same Hebrew
number same word by the word of the Lord
were the heavens made and all the hosts
of them by the breath of his mouth
the two times that the word of God
interacted on a large scale with with
the world is one at creation
and two
through Redemption
one at the creation of the world two
when he's just redeemed Israel from
their bondage in Egypt
that same word dabar
that created the heavens and the Earth
is
found in John chapter 1 and described as
the logos
I need you to hold that thought just
hold that thought for a second let's
read Genesis 2 verse 1 thus the heavens
and the Earth were finished and all the
hopes of them and on the seventh day God
ended his work which he had made and he
rested on the seventh day from all his
work which he had made I want you to
check something out here because I'm
about to show you the real reason why
most Christians are trying to get rid of
the tenderbars
in the Book of Genesis at the end of the
creative work of God he gives mankind
the Sabbath
that's the first time that the word of
God interacts on a on a massive scale
with the word with the world
the second time is in
Mount Sinai
and what does God give to man again
after he after he redeems them from
bondage
Deuteronomy 5 15 and remember that thou
was a servant in the land of Egypt and
that the Lord thy God brought the out
vents through a mighty hand and by its
stretched out arm therefore the Lord thy
God commanded thee to keep the Sabbath
day I need you to catch this the Sabbath
which is right in the middle of the Ten
Commandments
is the single Commandment that you find
present at both times that the word of
the Lord interacted with the world on a
massive scale
it was the sign of creation
it was the sign of redemption
and lo and behold
today many Christians in order to get
out of keeping that commandment have
cast aside the law all together
the reason why Christians teach so many
Christians teach that we don't need to
keep the Ten Commandments is not because
they believe it's all right for us to
steal or kill or lie or worse of graven
images or have other gods before us or
commit adultery or covet it's none of
those reasons they will never say yeah
it's okay to do that but the one
Commandment that they feel we don't need
to keep and we don't want to keep they
will they they decided we're just going
to teach
that all the Commandments The Ten
Commandments no longer we're no longer
under the law
not realizing that what they are
teaching is in direct contradiction to
the fact that God said this is going to
last for a thousand Generations
I need y'all to catch us I need your
under to understand this
so watch this we we got just a little
more to share here I want you to know
this in Exodus chapter 34 28.
the Bible says here and he was there
with the Lord speaking of Moses 40 days
and 40 nights and he did neither eat
bread nor drink water and he wrote upon
the tables the words of the Covenant The
Ten Commandments and again we already
see the Hebrew word is the bar now
check this out
in the Septuagint which is the Greek
version of the Old Testament this very
verse is translated I want you to note
what word they use to translate
commandments so instead of the bar which
would be Hebrew they're using Greek
guess what word that they use guess what
word they use
you see there on the screen
it's the word logos
the logos
the word that's how the Ten Commandments
are described and why is that
significant because in John 1 14 the
Bible uses this very word to describe
Christ and the word the logos was made
flesh and dwelt Among Us
please y'all understand this
we know that it was the word Jesus who
was there in the creation and it was
when those words were being spoken that
that was Jesus
he is the embodiment of power
it is that same logos
that same dabar
that same Rhema
that embodies the Ten Commandments
so if I can say it this way
to reject the Ten Commandments
is the very same thing as rejecting the
logos
he is the logos he is the law how do we
know this because the Bible says that
the law is love the Bible also says that
God is love so to claim to love God and
yet reject the law is it is it is
insanity this is why first John 2 3 says
this and hereby we do know that we know
him if we keep his Commandments he that
saith I know him and keepeth not his
Commandments is a liar and the truth is
not in him but watch this but whosoever
keepeth his word and what's the Greek
word here logos
who so keepeth his logos his Damar if we
were in the Old Testament in him verily
is the love of God perfected hereby we
know that we are in him do you see this
to reject
the Commandments of God
and yet claim Christ
is absolute hypocrisy
because the Commandments are the logos
if I can say this way if I were to say
to you tell me
who do you know that has never stolen
never lied never committed to those and
just gone through the Ten Commandments
never broken one what character would I
be describing who would I be describing
who would this law these Ten
Commandments
who would they personify
you'd have one answer and that answer is
Jesus
the Commandments are the very character
of Christ so to claim to love Jesus
while ignoring his Commandments the
Bible says it says that person is lying
they may be lying to themselves it may
not even be intentional they might just
be deceived but nonetheless it is
deception
Proverbs 13 13 says this who so
despiseth the word the bar shall be
destroyed but he that fear the
Commandment shall be rewarded
to reject the Commandments is to reject
Christ
bottom line the same as to reject Christ
is to reject the Commandments
Christians have a
958 year problem
in Isaiah 55 verse 11 it says so shall
my word be that goeth forth out of my
mouth let me ask you did the tender bars
go forth out of God's mouth in the same
way that let there be light went out of
God's mouth at creation yes the Bible
says so shall my word be that goeth
forth out of my mouth it shall not
return unto me void and yet here we have
many Christians trying to make it void
it is void now it no longer matters
those words that came out of God's mouth
are now void that's what Christians are
teaching
those words avoid them
those words spoken
to humanity
or void
God says it shall not return unto me
void but it shall accomplish that which
I please and it shall prosper in the
thing whereto I sent it and of course as
I already mentioned that word is the bar
right here in his verse
so
we summarize the problem
with this chart we're going to close
with this chart
how do you solve this problem
people who teach that the law of God was
done away with at the cross that the
dabar the tender Bars were done away
with at the cross how do you
how do you equate
a thousand Generations
how does a thousand Generations equal 42
Generations
why do you cut off those other 958
that extend beyond the cross
why do you cut it off can you explain
you know in math they say show your work
show us your work show us how you cut
off 958 Generations from what God Said
God's Own word says a thousand
Generations how do you cut off 958
how do you make void that which came out
of God's mouth
so there's the math challenge there's
the math problem this problem reveals
that the teaching that the Commandments
of God have been done away with
is a teaching that is not in accordance
with the word of God
yes we know
absolutely nobody is saved
by The Works that we do by the keeping
of The Commandments you can't kill
someone and then say hey I promise I'll
never kill someone again and then be
found innocent because you promise
you'll never kill someone again it's the
same thing all have sinned and even if
we kept the Commandments perfectly from
here on out that can't save us because
we've already sinned only the blood of
Christ can save us not anything we do
only the blood of Christ can save us so
we praise God for the cross
however
if I claim the cross but yet continue on
to break those Commandments yeah I'm
gonna you know lie and steal because
Jesus saved me so I I cannot go lie I
cannot go steal I can now go kill come
on
you know that doesn't make
you know that's not logic
it's not logical
so how do you explain this missing 958
Generations or let me say this way how
do you explain this 45
000 in 26 years that you just decided
yet no longer necessary
how do you take forever
and stop it at 42.
so there's your math problem
please
comment in the chat
and if you can't solve this problem
because it's not a problem that can be
solved y'all
there's no way to make this math work
it's God's map
or nothing
may you follow the truth
wherever it leads
and may this math problem
save your life may this math problem
guide you
to the truth regarding God's
Commandments and his Sabbath
God bless you
[Music]